BU Records: Dean of Women (Lily Russell), Inclusive: 1922-1969, undated, Bulk: 1935-1945
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
- Photographs, 1939-1942, undated; 10
  - Student Individuals, undated; 1
    - Sophomores (1 of 3), undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Sophomores (2 of 3), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Sophomores (3 of 3), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Beta Sigma Chi, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Senior Law (1 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Debate, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Junior Class Officers, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Freshmen Class Officers, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Senior Class Officers, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Alpha Psi Omega, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Urbanites, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Burleson Hall Council, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - International Club, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Peer Club, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Athenean Club, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Pi Gamma Mu, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Alpha Omega, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Sigma Tau Delta, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Kappa Delta Pi, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Press Club, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Esquire Club, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Freshmen (1 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Freshmen (2 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Freshmen (3 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Senior Law (2 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Brooks Hall Council, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Women’s Athletic Association, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Loose Portraits with Identification (1 of 3), undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Loose Portraits with Identification (2 of 3), undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Loose Portraits with Identification (3 of 3), undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Loose Portraits without Identification (1 of 2), undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Loose Portraits without Identification (2 of 2), undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Loose Photographs (1 of 2), undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Loose Photographs (2 of 2), undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Student Individuals Annual, 1939; 2
    - Women’s Athletic Association, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Debate, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Ars Nova, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Sigma Tau Delta, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Press Club, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Pre-Med Club, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - B.S.U. Council (Baptist Student Union Council), 1939 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - The Daily Lariat (1 of 2), 1939 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Rio Grande Valley Club, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Pi Gamma Mu, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Athenean Club, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Little Theatre, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Home Economics Club, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Pre-Law Club, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Beta Sigma Chi, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Classical Club, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - The Daily Lariat (2 of 2), 1939 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Phi Mu, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Loose Portraits with Identification (1 of 4), 1939 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Loose Portraits with Identification (2 of 4), 1939 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Loose Portraits with Identification (3 of 4), 1939 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Loose Portraits with Identification (4 of 4), 1939 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Loose Portraits without Identification, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Tennis (Sports), undated; 3
    - Photographs, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Student Individuals (Studio), undated; 4
    - Photographs, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Delta Sigma Pi, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Sophomore Class Officers, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Student Assistants, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Junior Class Officers, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Press Club, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Senior Class Officers, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Freshmen Class Officers, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Esquire Club, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - B.B.A. (Bachelor of Business Administration), undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Beta Beta Beta, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Annual Page, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Memorial Hall Council, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Delta Delta Delta, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Home Economics Club, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - D.A.P. (Delta Alpha Pi) Club, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Mid-Law, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Baylor Little Theatre, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Sophomore Class Officers, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Alpha Chi, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Baylor Twin Club, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Alexander House Council, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Freshmen, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Student Assistants, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Faculty, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Juniors (1 of 4), undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Juniors (2 of 4), undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Pre-Med Club, undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Pi Mu Alpha Sinfonia, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Console Club, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - French Theatre, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Mu Phi Epsilon, undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Alpha Epsilon Delta, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Alpha Rho Tau, undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Rio Grande Valley Club, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Classical Club, undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Juniors (3 of 4), undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Juniors (4 of 4), undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Sophomores, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Seniors (1 of 3), undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Seniors (2 of 3), undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Seniors (3 of 3), undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Loose Portraits with Identification (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Loose Portraits with Identification (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Loose Portraits without Identification, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Uncut Portraits (1 of 6), undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Uncut Portraits (2 of 6), undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Uncut Portraits (3 of 6), undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Uncut Portraits (4 of 6), undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Uncut Portraits (5 of 6), undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Uncut Portraits (6 of 6), undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Identification Cards, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Student Pictures, 1941-1942; 5
    - Uncut Portraits (1 of 6), 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Uncut Portraits (2 of 6), 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Uncut Portraits (3 of 6), 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Uncut Portraits (4 of 6), 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Uncut Portraits (5 of 6), 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Uncut Portraits (6 of 6), 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Datebooks, 1927-1938; 11
  This series contains Lily Russell’s datebooks during her time as Assistant Dean of Women, Acting Dean of Women and Dean of Women. In these books Russell logged her daily activities and appointments.
  - Datebook, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Datebook, 1928 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Datebook, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Datebook, 1930 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Datebook, 1931 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Datebook, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Datebook, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Datebook, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Datebook, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Datebook, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Datebook, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Datebook, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Forms, 1929-1942, undated; 12
  This series consolidated folders labeled “Forms” and “Old Form Letters.” All folders contained an assortment of blank forms, templates for letters, and letters that were written and kept as prototypes for future use. The blank forms include applications, surveys, and other requests for information. Letter templates often contain the bulk of text needed to produce a letter with space provided to include personalization. Copies of letters sent to various people (students, parents, educators, etc.) were retained for future reference and often have handwritten annotations and instructions regarding formatting and situation. The letters provide insight to the scope of Lily Russell’s responsibilities as Dean of Women. Subjects discussed in the letters include admissions, student employment, dormitory housing, and event coordination. The series includes items written by Russell’s predecessor as Dean of Women, Irene Marschall, and successor, Sadie T. Crawley. Also, seemingly unrelated items such as residence lists for dormitories from 1941-1943 were present. The series is in poor condition and many documents have been damaged by moisture.
  - Forms, 1929-1942, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Old Form Letters, 1928-1939, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Dormitories, 1931-1940, 1964, undated; 13
  This series chronicles Lily Russell’s involvement with the dormitories at Baylor University. As Dean of Women, Russell was highly involved in female student placement and staffing of the dormitories. The Management subseries consolidated Russell’s documentation of her involvement with Baylor’s dormitories. Materials include those related to dormitory management (documentation and correspondence regarding occupancy, staff, reports, and announcements), and maintenance issues (itemized damages, purchase lists, and proposed projects). Two deviations from the original arrangement are present in the Management subseries. The Instructions folder consolidated two folders that contained directions for staff. Some drafts are included in addition to personalized copies. The Summer School folder was created from items Russell identified as “Summer School.” These materials are related to dormitory occupancy in the summer months.
  Near the end of her tenure as Dean of Women, Russell was involved with the completion of Catherine Alexander Dormitory. The Catherine Alexander Dormitory subseries were created from a file transferred from the BU Records: Dean of the Union Building (Lily Russell) collection. The beginning of the transferred material was mostly correspondence about repairs and receipts for multiple dormitories, and those items have been separated. The remainder of the series is primarily comprised of Russell’s correspondence with vendors regarding the design and furnishing of Catherine Alexander Hall. Included are estimates, receipts and lists of vendors. During this time, Russell was also ordering items for Burleson Hall, so a few documents refer to both dormitories. The series is in poor condition, and several items in the series have been damaged by moisture.
  - Management, 1931-1940, undated; 1
    - Dormitory Management, 1932-1940, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Estimates and Repairs, 1931-1937, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Instructions, 1938, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Guests, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Song Copies, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Summer School, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Catherine Alexander Dormitory, 1938-1940, 1964, undated; 2
    - Estimates and Repairs, 1938-1939, 1964, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Catherine Alexander Dormitory (1 of 2), 1938-1940, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Catherine Alexander Dormitory (1 of 2), 1938-1940, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Literary Productions, 1940; 14
  This series contains materials collected by Lily Russell during her time as Dean of Women and contains materials related to the education of women.
  - Albion College Bulletin, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 7)